군대 안가봐서 계급도 잘 모르고
발번역,오역의역오타난무하니 대충보시길
관타나모 기지로 가는데...
_
거기 가는데 얼마나 걸릴진 모르겠어
막으라고? 어떻게?
_
알았어 해볼게
해본다니깐
_
새 회로를 위해 20개의
엠프가 필요하고
We'll need another
20 amps for a new circuit,
노트북 3대
외장하드 4개개 더 필요해요
at least 3 more laptops,
and 4 external hard drives.
- 예
- 거기두세요
- Yes, ma'am.
- You can leave that right there.
- 고마워 - 예.
- 저기?
- Thank you. - Yes, ma'am.
- Well?
우리에게 필요한 걸
줄거야
They're gonna get us
what we need.
그 말은
If you mean to do this,
샘플을 위해 더 포괄적인
쿨링시스템이 필요하단거야?
we're gonna need a much more
comprehensive cooling system
for the specimens.
여러번 말해뒀어
And I have told them as much.
물약병, 주사기--
모든게 다 떨어져가고 있어
Vials, syringes--
We're running low on everything.
퀸시, 나도 알아.
Quincy, I know.
관타나모 기지에 도착하면
보충할거야
We will replenish
once we get to Guantanamo Bay.
질문할테니
대답해 봐
I'm going to ask you a question,
and I want you to listen to me.
해봐
Go ahead.
하루 20시간 일하고
잠도 안잤어
You're working 20 hours a day,
you're not sleeping.
스프린트(단거리 질주)가
아닌 마라톤이야
This is a marathon,
not a sprint.
이번에 배에서 날 내리게 해줘
Let me
go off-ship this time.
생각해볼게
I'll think about it.
발사 준비!
Ready! Up!
발사!
Fire!
준비! 제자리 섯!
Ready! Halt!
헤드 샷!
Head shot!
총 안전위치로!
Weapons on safe!
전에 말했듯이 오른쪽 팔에
끼워넣고 자세를 취한다
Like I said,
keep that right arm locked,
그리고 반동에 확실하게 몸을 기댄다
and make sure you lean
into that recoil.
알겠습니다.
Yes, sir.
- 다음 그룹!
- 보기에 어떤가?
- Next group!
- How they looking?
제노위츠는 눈썰미가 있고,
해리스와 코세티는 배짱이 있습니다
Janowitz has an eye, Harris
and Cossetti have the balls.
그곳에선 배짱이 필요하고
결정되기도 합니다
Depends on what we're gonna need
out there, sir.
배짱이라
우린 배짱이 필요하지
Balls.
We need the balls.
Yes, sir
Yes, sir.
전술 1팀 진군!
Tac Team 1-- advance!
전술 2팀 let's go!
Tac 2, let's go!
진군!
Advance!
이런 썅 , 밀러!
Damn it, Miller!
총구가 내려갔잖아!
Muzzle down!
죄송합니다!
Sorry, sir!
Gitmo에서 적의 대가릴 날릴 때
Sorry's not
gonna do nettles any good
죄송하단 말은 아무 소용없다
when you shoot his head off
at Gitmo!
전술 1, 전술 2 리셋!
다시한다
Now Tac 1, Tac 2 reset!
Do it again!
시간 좀 걸릴 것 같습니다
It's gonna take time, sir.
시간이든 뭐든 우린 없네
Time is something
we don't have.
매일 집에도 못가고
백신이 없어
Every day we don't come home
with a vaccine
하루에 50만명의 사람이 죽고있지
is a day another
half a million people die.
전 그냥 저들이 제대로
준비됐으면 합니다
I just want to make sure
they're ready.
자넨 그렇게 할거야
You'll get them there.
Yes, sir
Yes, sir.
전술팀1 진군!
Tac Team 1-- advance!
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
상황팀으로 3명이서 10시간
교대로 작업하게 될거야
You will operate on three-man
watch teams, 10-hour shifts.
함장님께 모든 교신 내용은
함장님께 보고한다
Captain wants a complete log
of every transmission.
전 세계의 비상방송,무선 구조요청을 수신하되
You may be hearing
emergency broadcast
and ham-radio distress calls
from around the world,
어떤 상항에서도
응답하거나 교신하지 않는다.
but we do not,
under any circumstances,
respond or transmit.
엄격하게 전파방사통제하고
보안을 유지해야한다
Strict EMCON.
Our position must remain secure.
러시아는 우릴 계속 쫓고 있습니까?
So the Russians
are still following us.
그건 모른다
We don't know that.
누군가 핵무기를 프랑스로 쏴서
우리 머리위로 지나가게 했던데..
Well, somebody shot a nuke
over our heads outside France.
5일동안 CIC에 있었지?
CIC(전투정보실)
You been in CIC
the last five days?
예
Yes, ma'am.
조그만 증후라도 감지한게 있었나?
Were there any surface
or subsurface contacts?
없습니다
No, ma'am.
그럼, 루머는 퍼지지 않게 하도록
Then let's not start
spreading rumors.
바이러스처럼
치명적이니까
They can be
as contagious as the virus.
이 객실은 통신요원들만
출입가능하다 알겠나?
This room
will be restricted access--
comms specialists only.
Got it?
예
Yes, ma'am.
수석엔지니어!
상황보고 하도록
Chief Engineer,
give me a status!
선박의 연료는 전적으로
지저분하고 정격감소중입니다
Sir, the fuel
from the cruise ship
is absolutely filthy
and just keeps degrading.
만약에 Gitmo에서 수확이 없다면
노를 저어야할 상황이 올겁니다
If we don't hit pay dirt at Gitmo,
we might as well break out the oars.
알았네, 노즐을 통해 연소하면 안되겠군
노즐-증기,디젤기관의 터빈 분출장치
All right, well, we don't want
to burn through our nozzles.
좀더 나은 엔진 두어개는 작동시키지 말게
Better take
a couple engines offline.
그럴 수 없습니다
No can do, sir.
부대장님께서 Gitmo 까지
전속력으로 가라고 하셨습니다.
CO's ordered flank speed
all the way to Gitmo.
연료상태를 알고 계시나?
And he's up to date
on the condition of the fuel?
예 알고 계십니다
He is, sir.
여깄다 얘야
Here you go, boy.
훈련은 어떻게 되가?
How's training going?
글쎄, 난 뭘 위한
훈련인지 잘 모르겠다
Well, I don't know exactly
what we're training for.
그저 시체 더미를 찾는건지..
Just gonna find
a bunch of corpses.
프랭키를 대신할 놈을
찾는 훈련인데 힘들겠지
Must be tough, having to train
someone to replace Frankie.
난 이 쓰레기들이 진절머리 나
I'm getting sick of this crap.
으깬 감자가 아닌
다른 뭔가를 찾길바래
I hope we find something
other than mashed potatoes
쿠바의
클링피치라든지 (씨가 잘 분리되지 않는 복숭아)
and cling peaches in Cuba.
대니...
Danny...
왜?
What?
넌 어쩔 수 없는 거였어
You're not dealing.
프랭키는 죽었어
Frankie's dead.
아마 내 부모님, 너의 부모님도
So are my parents, probably,
and so are yours,
다른이들도 다...
everyone else's
in the whole damn world.
그래서,정확히 내가
어쩔 수 있는건 뭔데?
So what exactly is the
proper way for me to be dealing?
저흰 식량,물이 떨어져 갑니다
We're low on food, low on water.
도움이 필요합니다
We need help.
17번 도로에서
떨어진 창고에 있습니다
We're in a warehouse
off of Route 17.
제 두 아들과 함께 그러니까...
I'm with my two boys, so--
...제 목소리.
...my voice.
의료지원이 필요합니다 부탁드립니다.
We need medical assistance,
please.
우린 즉각.....
We are right off...
공개적으로 말하기가 좀 그렇지만
I don't really feel comfortable
speaking in public, but...
아이오와주에 어디쯤에 계신
어머니께 말하고 싶습니다.
I just wanted to say something
about my mother,
하느님
who's in Iowa, somewhere,
I hope.
어머니를 안전하게
보살펴 주시옵소서
God, please look over her
and keep her safe.
어머님의 성함이 뭔가?
What's her name, son?
Barbara
Barbara.
Barbara Miller입니다
Barbara Miller.
이게(사진) 제 어머니입니다
This is her.
남자친구를 위해 기도하고 싶습니다
I'd like to say a prayer
for my boyfriend.
남친의 이름(성)은 미키이고
His name's Mickey.
그러니까,이름(이름)은 모리스입니다
Well, his real name's Morris.
어... 남친..
Uh, he...
남친은 사진 찍는걸
싫어합니다..그래서 음..
he hates having
his picture taken, so, um...
구한게 이 것 한장뿐입니다.
I've just got this one.
selfie(셀프 카메라)입니다
It's a-- it's a selfie.
이 사진은 제 아버지 폴,
네이트와 로니 제 남동생들입니다
This is my father, Paul,
my brothers Nate and Ronnie.
다들 어디에 있는지
몰라서 연락을 할 수가 없습니다
Couldn't get through to them,
so I don't know where they are.
대부분 사람들이
우리들과 마찬가지일겁니다
Like most of us, I guess.
하지만, 음...
But, um...
나를 계속 지탱 하는건
what keeps me going is the idea
우리가 어딘가에 있는
그들을 도울 수 있다는 생각입니다
that we might be able
to help them somehow.
어쩌면 이유가 있을겁니다
You know,
maybe there was a reason
우린 그간 북극에 있었습니다
we were out there in the Arctic
all that time.
아마 이건 우리에게
내린 하나님의 계획일겁니다
Maybe this is God's plan
for us.
Amen
Amen to that.
Amen.
바이러스는 이런 규칙이 있습니다.
The rules of the virus
are these--
공기중에 떠 다니고 즉,
보균자에게 전염될 수 있습니다
it's airborne,
which means you can get it
from anyone who's a carrier--
어떤 사람은 질병에서 나타나고 있고,
심지어 최근에 죽은시체에서도 말이죠
anyone manifesting the disease,
even a recently deceased corpse.
전형적인 증상은 기침,어지러움
Typical symptoms
are lethargy and a cough,
다음으론 염증과 출혈이고
followed by bleeding sores
and hemorrhaging,
끝으론, 치매와 전체 혈액소실입니다.
ending in dementia
and total blood loss.
잠복기는 얼마나 됩니까?
How long
is the incubation period?
3~5일 입니다.
Three to five days.
제가 아는 바이며,지난번
질병관리센터에 연락해 알아낸겁니다
At least,
that's what I understood
from my last contact
with the CDC.
그게 언제입니까?
And when was that?
북극에 있었던 3주 전입니다.
Three weeks ago, when we
were still up in the Arctic.
잠복기가 바뀔 수 있다는 겁니까?
A-are you saying the incubation
period can change?
바이러스는 몇 시간동안 돌연변이되고 있었습니다
The virus has been mutating
for some time,
그건 인위적으로 변화하던게
although I believe that now that
it's been artificially altered,
안정됐다고 믿고 있지만..
it's been stabilized.
믿는다고요?
You "believe"?
동물들은 어떻습니까?
What about animals?
halsey(멍멍이 이름)를 걱정하는거면,
If you're concerned
about Halsey,
개는 면역 돼 있습니다
dogs happen to be immune.
다른 동물들은 병에 걸릴 수 있고,
Other animals
can contract the disease.
인간에겐 전염되진 않습니다.
They just can't transmit it
to humans.
생각해보니 북극에서
새들이 최초의 보균자였는데
Thought the birds
from the Arctic
were the original carriers.
새들이 최초의 보균자인건 맞는데
The birds
were the original carriers.
바이러스가 급격히 바뀌었죠
The virus jumped,
아마 새똥에서 포유동물로 옮기고
probably from their feces
to a mammal
우리에게 닥치기 전엔
돌연변이중이었을거에요
before mutating
and landing on us.
여러번 돌연변이 후
인위적으로 변했을테고
After several mutations,
it was artificially altered.
그게 돌연변이된 변종버전입니다.
It is that version
of the mutated strain
현재 우리 지구에
재앙을 일으키고 있고요
that is currently
devastating our planet.
그래서,개방된 외부공간을 제외하고는
항상 CBR장비(화생방 장비)를 쓰고,
So, CBR gear at all times,
except outside in open spaces,
마스크로 산소 공급을 하죠
masks can be off
to preserve your oxygen.
내부에서는?
And inside?
한명의 감염자가 배 전체를
숨쉬는 것만으로 위험하게 할 수 있으니..
One infected person could
jeopardize this entire ship...
simply by breathing.
격리시켜야죠..
위험지역으로 가기 전에
질문있습니다
Question-- Before we send
our men into a hot zone,
바이러스가 돌연변이를 계속하고,
if the virus keeps mutating
거의 한달동안
고향 소식도 못 듣는 상황에서
and you haven't heard
from homeland in almost a month,
당신이 말한 것을 어떻게 확신에
확신을 할 수 있습니까
how could you be sure
of what you're so sure of?
제가 한말에 의심의 여지가 있었다면
If I had any doubt
about what I was saying...
말해드렸겠죠
I would tell you.
그랬기를 바랍니다
I would hope so.
분위기 싸하게 만드는
재주가 있군
I see you've cooled off.
전 괜찮은데요
I'm fine.
왜 그랬나?
What was that?
그냥 질문한거였습니다
Just asking questions.
자넨 장교 앞에서
그녀를 망신주려는거였어
You were undermining her
in front of the officers.
마이크 나도 알아
I know, Mike.
그녀는 4달 동안
우리한테 거짓말했어
She lied to us for four months.
예, 그리고
그녀는 매주 본국과 연락하면서
Yeah, and while she
was talking to home every week,
우린 가족들에게
경고해줄 기회조차 없었죠
we didn't even get a chance
to warn our families.
저흰 그저 참아야할 뿐입니까?
We're just supposed to
get over that?
응, 그래야지
Yeah, we are.
그녀는 제 신뢰를 얻기엔
멀리 갔습니다.
Well, she's got a long way to go
before she earns my trust.
That's all.
그러는 난?
What about me?
해군도 없고 ,그 조직도 없고
There's no Navy,
no infrastructure,
식량이나 보급도 없네
no food or fuel supply.
어디에서
뭘 찾아야 할지도 모르고,
We don't know what
we're gonna find anywhere we go,
모든 것들을 있는 걸로
즉석으로 해야되지
and we're gonna have to
improvise every step of the way.
우리가 본부가 되야할 것 같아
Now,
I'm gonna need my XO--
라인을 벗어나는 겁니까?
To fall in line?
누가 뭐라건
To execute...
우린 작전을 수행한다
whether or not he agrees
with my decisions.
이제 한번만 물어보겠네
Now, I'm gonna ask you one time
and one time only--
내 말 알아듣었지?
Are you with me?
전 맹세했고, 여전히
지휘 계통을 존중합니다
I took an oath, and I still
respect the chain of command.
그걸 묻는게 아닐텐데
That wasn't my question.
알겠습니다.
I'm with you.
정말로 그녀가 할 수
있을거라 생각하십니까?
You really think
she can do this?
그녀가 유일한 희망이야
She's the only hope we got.
이제 Gitmo 입니다
Coming over Gitmo now.
시야엔 아무도 없음
Negative visual contact.
움직임 없음
Negative movement.
다들 어딨지?
Where is everybody?
기류 흐름 동일.
Same on thermals.
우린 수평,수직상태이고
copy,지상엔 움직임 없음
We have zero, copy,
zero ground movement.
저기에 9000명이 주둔해 있었는데
There were 9,000 people
stationed there.
식량창고와 병원들이
아래 펼쳐있고,
The food warehouse and the
hospital are pretty spread out.
연료탱크는 저기 있다
Fuel rig's
all the way up there.
우리가 3팀으로 가는 이유이다.
That's why we're gonna go
with three teams.
난 식량창고를 맡는다.
I'll take the food warehouse.
자넨 병원,
연료팀 준비됐나?
You'll get the hospital.
Fuel team ready?
준비 됐습니다
We are, sir.
긴장해
Stay frosty.
뭔가 느낌이 좋지 않아
Something about this
doesn't feel right.
알겠습니다
Yes, sir.
내가 본 사람들중에선
제일 고집불통이야
You're absolutely the most
obstinate person I've ever met.
너도 그렇게 생각하지?
You know that, don't you?
글쎄,만난 사람들을 다 모르잖아
Well, I don't know everyone
that you've ever met.
이건 미친짓이야
It's insane.
널 나가게 냅두면
일주일 내내 거기 있으려고할 걸
If I let you go,
you'll be out there all week.
퀸시 넌 너무 신중해
You're too meticulous, Quince.
무슨 일이 일어나면 어쩌려고?
What if something happens
to you?
맞아요, 당신을 배 밖으로 보내
모험을 할 수 없습니다.
He's right. We can't risk
you leaving the ship.
고맙습니다
제 작업복은 제가 챙기죠
Thank you.
I'll get my suit.
토펫 박사보고 가라는건 아니오
Not so fast, Dr. Tophet.
우린 당신들중 누구하나
위험에 처하게할 수 없소
We can't risk
either one of you.
염려는 고맙지만
That's flattering, but--
우리에게 어떻게 물자를
줄 계획이신데요?
How do you plan
on getting us the supplies?
그러니까 제 말은 당신들을
과소평가 하는게 아니고
I mean, not to underestimate
your men's capabilities,
우리가 뭘 필요로 하는지
정확히 알 것 같지 않다는 거죠
but it's highly unlikely
they're going to be able
to identify what we need.
우린 하늘위에 있는 ICBM
(대륙간탄도미사일)을 요격도 할 수 있으니
We can knock an ICBM
out of the sky.
우린 잘해낼 수 있을겁니다.
I think we can handle this.
CIC(전투 정보 지휘소)
장교가 당신들을 호위할거요
An officer
will escort you both to CIC.
함장님 무엇보다도
And what about you, Captain?
함장님께 무슨 일이 생긴다면요?
What if something happens
to you?
유능한 슬래터리 중령 지휘하에
The mission will go on
in Commander Slattery's
very capable hands.
임무는 수행될거요
지난 밤 일 후론 믿음이 안가는군요
After last night's performance,
I'm not so sure.
이런...
Well...
우린 한배를 탄 사람들이오
그렇지 않소?
we're all out on a limb here,
aren't we?
독수리팀은 동쪽 해변에 상륙해서
Vulture Team is feet dry
on the east beach.
첫 번째 목표물로 간다다
Proceed to first objective.
남쪽 게이트로 접근중
Approaching the south gate.
코브라팀 병원으로 접근중
Cobra Team
is approaching the hospital.
이쪽입니다
Over here.
그린 중위님 헬멧에 캠을 달아놨습니다.
We've attached a helmet cam
to Lieutenant Green.
우린 그가 하는 것들을 UHF로
모두 볼 수 있고 소통할 수 있습니다
We can see everything he does
and communicate to him by UHF
그러니까 박사님이 필요한 걸
정확히 말해주세요
so you get
exactly what you need.
괜찮을겁니다
It'll be fine.
제 자리에요
That's my chair.
저 사람들은 특히 저를
Look, I understand
안 좋아하는걸 알아요
that people aren't particularly
thrilled with me,
하지만 전 국방부로부터
지시를 받았죠
but I had orders
from the Pentagon.
저희도 압니다
We understand orders.
저희도 항상 따른답니다
We follow them every day.
가자
Let's go.
마스크 착용
Whoa. Whoa. Masks on. Masks on.
All right, mask up.
산소공급시간은 최대 60분이다
We got 60 minutes of air,
max conserve.
린 참모총장님 부함장 연료팀
(석유)굴착장치로 접근중입니다
Chief Lynn, XO-- Fuel Team's
approaching the rigs.
연료공급 15분즘
걸릴 것으로 예상됩니다
Expect to receive fuel
within 15 minutes.
알겠네 부함장
Roger, XO.
밸브휠을 찾아야 하는데
We need
to find the valve wheel.
멀리 가지는 마.
Couldn't have gone far.
독수리팀 남쪽 지역으로
향하는중
Vulture Team
heading through south sector.
조용합니다
All's quiet.
이런, 실버스타에 기를 쓰던
밀러 아냐?(명예 훈장)
Well, you're bucking for a
silver star, aren't you, Miller?
정신 똑바로 차려
Can't teach courage like that.
지시를 따라라
Follow our lead.
우린 한시간 내로 끝내야 해
We'll be in and out
in less than an hour.
지나쳤습니까
Too much?
적당하네
Just enough.
만지지 마십시오
Don't touch that.
그게 빠지면
엔지니어링 객실을
You discharge that,
you'll flood
할론 가스로 가득 메우게 됩니다
the whole engineering room
with poisonous halon gas.
어, 제 객실이 추워서 말이오
Uh, my stateroom is freezing,
그리고 제가 있는 곳은
and I was told
one of these levers
에어컨을 꺼달라고 말했었는데.
might shut off the AC
to my space.
누구한테요?
By who?
저도 모릅니다
I don't know.
어...사병중 한명이겠죠
Uh...
One of the enlisted men.
그냥 저희에게 부탁하시고
Just--
just do us a favor--
배 안에서 뭐든 만지지
말아주십시오 알겠습니까?
don't touch anything
on the ship, okay?
물론이죠
Of course.
도움이 필요하시면
요청하십시오
You need help, you ask for it.
물론이죠, 정말 죄송합니다
Of course.
Very sorry.
오케이
Okay.
정면을 봐
Eyes in front of you.
마스크 안에 토하면 안돼
You do not puke in your mask.
유람선도 하고 똑같네요?
Is that what it was like
on the cruise ship?
아무도 인정하고 싶지 않겠지만
None of them want
to talk about it.
할 말이 없네요
That's because
there are no words.
나단 제임스 호랑이팀
준비완료
Nathan James, Tiger Team--
we're all set.
알겠다
Copy that.
(연료)공급받을 준비됐습니다
We are ready to receive.
CCS, Bridge--
그쪽으로 마티니가 보내는중
your Martini is on its way.
1, 2, 3!
한 번 더
해보자.
One more time.
We got it.
1, 2, 3!
Bridge, CCS--
연료 공급받고 있습니다
fueling commenced.
내부로 진입.
We're in.
스테로이드,인터페론,리바비린을
Right,
you're looking for steroids,
Interferon, Ribavirin,
아무 항생물질들을 찾아주세요
찾을 수 있을거에요
any broad-spectrum antibiotics
you can find.
우린 방역복,평판배양을
볼 모니터 장치도 필요합니다
We need plastic wear, monitoring
equipment, culture plates.
실내 전체를 보여주세요
Show me the whole room.
천천히 보여주세요
Bring it 'round slowly.
오른쪽
Over to the right.
뒤로,뒤로, 뒤로 왼쪽
Back, back, back!
Back to the left.
앞으로 가까이 가보세요
Move forward, closer.
그거에요
That's it!
그게 원심분리기에요
That's a centrifuge.
찰리 5지구 뚜렷한
움직임 없습니다
No apparent activity
in sector Charlie 5.
독수리팀 바로 목표물에 접근중
Vulture Team proceeding
directly to objective.
알겠다, 독수리 1
Copy that, Vulture 1.
마스크들 착용
Masks.
난 미국인이요
I'm an American!
거기서 당장 나와요
Get the hell out of there!
멈춰!
Stop! Stop!
Stop it!
당장 나오라니까!
Get the hell out of there!
일어나,전진한다
Get up, get up! Get going!
전투준비!
Weapons!
진정해요! 진정
Take it easy! Easy!
난 적이 아니오
I'm friendly!
난 적이 아니오 미국인이오
I'm friendly, American!
독수리1 알 수 없는
적에게 공격 받았음
This is Vulture 1, under attack
by unknown number of hostiles.
포격준비
Stand by for fire mission.
총원전투배치!
상항 레드 발령
Set general quarters!
Threat warning red!
발사준비!
Weapons tight!
총원전투배치!
General quarters!
총원 모두 전투위치로!
All hands,
man your battle stations!
5-1지역에서 약간
Light off mount 5-1.
벗어나서 위치조정이 필요합니다
Shift to local ready surface.
독수리 1, 나단 제임스
타겟 잡혔습니까?
Vulture 1, Nathan James--
do we have a target?
안잡힘.
Negative.
코브라팀,호랑이팀 통보한다
Cobra Team, Tiger Team--
be advised--
이 지역은 적들이 할동중
hostiles operating on base.
감시를 강화하고
IEDs are being employed.
FIPCOM은 델타로 설정한다
Set FIPCOM Delta.
알겠습니다, 독수리 1.
Copy that, Vulture 1.
원사님,주변경계하겠습니다!
Master Chief, we need guns
up on the perimeter!
알겠네. 오코너!
I'm on it. O'Connor!
여긴 코브라팀
This is Cobra Team.
우린 그쪽에서 남남동 지역으로
0.5마일 떨어져있습니다
We're a half-mile
south-southeast
from your port ops.
저흰 후방에서 지원하겠습니다.
Say the word
and we will provide backup.
아니다
Negative.
상황만 복잡해질 뿐인다
I don't want you walking
into an ambush.
임무를 계속 수행하도록
Stay on mission.
Yes, sir.
물러서!
Back up!
이런 염병할
난 당신들 편이라고!
Jesus, guys, I'm on your side!
물러서라고 했다
I said back up!
난 감염되지 않다고요
I'm not sick!
심지어 폭팔물로 당신들
죽이려던 놈들도 감염이 안됐고
Even the assbags who tried
to kill you are not sick!
자,엄호 하고,
저 남자를 이쪽으로 오게한다
All right, set cover,
but let him come.
좋아,천천히 걸어 오시오
All right, step forward!
Slowly!
이봐요!
Hey, hey, hey!
천천히 오라고요!
Keep it slow!
천천이 움직이시오.
Moving slow.
모두 진정하세요
Everybody just take it easy.
이 정도 거리면 충분하오
That's far enough.
오케이,제독님 사정을
알고 싶지 않소?
Okay, Commodore, you want
to get the lowdown or not?
폭발물에 대해 말해보시오
Let's start with the assbags.
알카에다가 한거요
They're Al-Qaeda.
-어쨋든,걔들이 놓고 간거지?
-몇 명이나 있소?
- What's left of them, anyway.
- How many?
모두 14명이지만
당신들 환영파티를
14 altogether,
but they're spread out now
위해 다들 떨어져 있어요
to make you a welcoming party.
아무도 감염 안됐다고?
Nobody's sick?
우리는 모두 7구역에 있었는데
We were all
in Section 7--
본부와는 완전히 떨어져 격리되어서
isolated part of the camp
for high-level detainees.
음식도 시설도 다 따로 써왔소
We had our own food stocks,
own facilities.
다른 사람들은 다 대피했소
None of us came in contact
with the virus.
아무도 바이러스에
감염되지 않았고
Everybody else was evacuated.
그 장소는 우리가 접수했소
We had the run of the place.
- "우리"?
-저와 다른 6명의 요원요
- "We"?
- Me and six other guards.
간수,
민간경호 말이요
Subcontractors,
private security.
정부,정치도
없어진 마당에..
That point, we figured,
no governments, no politics.
그들을 풀어주었소
We let them go.
그랬더니 배신 했군
And they turned on you.
남은 내 베프는 저렇게 됐고
That's what's left
of my best friend.
나머지놈들은 행방불명이요
Other guy's MIA.
지금은 혼자 여기 있고요
I'm the last man standing.
그래서 그들은 어디 있는데요?
So where the hell are they?
대부분 식품창고를
보호하기 위해 갔었는데
Most of them went
to guard the food warehouse,
적어도 3명은 당신들 배를
털기 위해 로켓포를 가지고 갔소
but at least three of them
peeled off towards your ship
with rocket launchers.
왜 이졔 얘기하는거요?
You're just
telling me this now?
계속 질문했잖소
You're the one
asking the questions.
나단 제임스,여긴 독수리 1
통보한다,
Nathan James, Vulture 1--
be advised,
적들은 로켓포를 무장하고 있고
hostiles are armed with RPGs
위스키쪽으로 이동중인 것 같다.
and appear to be en route
to your whiskey.
호랑이 1, 나단 제임스
펌프질 중지
Tiger 1, Nathan James--
cease pumping.
-즉시 중단
-연료공급 중지
- Shut it down now.
- Secure fueling.
그래, 식품창고에 대해
말해줄 수 있소?
So, what can you tell me
about this food warehouse?
어떻게 가야하는지
알려드릴 수 있어요
I can tell you
how to get in there,
그치만 당신 손이
더러워 질 수 있어요
but it's gonna mean
getting your hands dirty.
전에도 지저분 했소
I've dirtied them before.
미 해군 함장 톰 첸들러요
나단 제임스
Tom Chandler,
CO Nathan James, US Navy.
텍스 노런
Gitmo에 오신걸 환영하오
Tex Nolan.
Welcome to Gitmo.
15PSI밖에 안 남았네
Man, only got 15 PSI.
젠장. 난 9% 남았어.
Shit. I'm at 9%.
자 제군들 내 말 잘들어
All right, guys, listen to me.
여기서 해야할 일을
아직 끝내지 못했지
We got a job to do here,
and we're not finished yet.
보급품,백신이 없으면
No supplies, no vaccine.
집에 갈 수도 없고
가족들을 만날 수 없다
No vaccine, no going home,
no seeing your families.
그린 중위님,머뭇거릴 시간 없어요
Lieutenant Green, please don't
take any more chances.
날 따라와
Follow my lead.
10분 안에 여기서 탈출한다
알겠나?
We'll be out of here
in less than 10, got it?
빨리 수행하자
Let's do this thing.
제 말 들리는거죠?
Did he hear me?
네 듣고계십니다
He heard you.
Bridge, CCS--
계속 연료공급되고 있습니다
We're still taking on fuel.
호랑이팀,무슨 일인가?
Tiger Team, what the hell's
going on down there?
밸브가 안움직입니다
돌려보고 있습니다
The valve is frozen!
We're working on it, sir!
제발!
Come on!
물러서세요
Ma'am, stand back.
부함장님, 호스를 외곽에서
떼어 내야 되요
XO, recommend disengaging
the fuel hose on our end.
적은 로켓포가 있으니 기름 흐르는건..
And spill the oil into the
harbor while they have RPGs?
젠장
Hell, no.
TAO, Bridge--
적이 다가오고 있다
We have hostiles incoming.
타겟을 찾아라
Find me a target.
다시 1, 2...
Again. 1, 2...
Nathan James,
밸브가 망가졌어요
the valve stem is shot, sir.
멈출 수가 없습니가
We cannot stop the fuel.
온다!
Incoming!
Aah!
Ma'am!
나단 제임스MPA입니다.
Aah!
Nathan James, this is MPA.
기술팀장이 맞았습니다
The Chief Engineer's been hit.
의사를 보내주십시오!
We need the doc up here, ASAP!
TAO,
목표물을 설정하라
give me a targeting solution
- 연료관제 터미널이다.
- 알겠습니다.
- on that fuel-maintenance terminal.
- Aye, sir.
OS 1, 거리,각도 조정이 되었나?
OS 1, range and bearing
to the terminal?
대략 220에 1500야드입니다
Rough bearing 220,
approximately 1,500 yards.
연료탱크로 가고 있음
They're going
for the fuel tank.
배 전체를 날려버릴 생각일거에요
They're gonna blow
the whole ship!
CIC, Bridge--
목표물 감지되었나?
Where's my target acquisition?
좌현 30도
Slew left 30.
알겠다. 좌현30도
Roger that.
30 degrees.
Bridge, Surface--
목표물 고정
Target acquired.
발사
Fire.
호랑이팀 나단 제임스--
리오스박사 이동중
Tiger Team, Nathan James--
Doc Rios is en route.
예상 시간 5분이다
ETA five minutes.
독수리, 코브라, 나단 제임스--
감지된 적들 섬멸되었다
Vulture, Cobra, Nathan James--
all known hostiles neutralized
연료 부두 근방이다
in the vicinity
of the fuel pier.
여기는 독수리팀, 알았다
Vulture Team, copy that.
어디에 있습니까?
So, where are they gonna be?
오트밀과 구운콩이 있죠
Oatmeal and baked beans--
it's the new women and children.
식료품 창고 안에 있구요
They're holed up
in that warehouse.
끌어들여서 우릴 잡으려고 할껍니다.
They're gonna make us
come in and get them.
함장님
Captain.
짐승새끼들
Animals.
복수심에 눈이 멀면 안돼요
Revenge is best served cold.
다 죽여버리겠어.
Let's eat.
그린 중위님
필요한건 다 챙겼으니
Lieutenant Green,
you have everything I need.
이제 나오세요
Please get out of there now.
코브라 1, 알겠다
Cobra 1, copy.
나가자
Proceeding to extract.
가자!
Go!
코브라팀이 병원에 갖혔습니다
Sir, Cobra Team's
trapped inside the hospital!
산소가 떨어지고 있는데..
They're running out of air.
병원 밖의 적들을 찾아봤나?
You're looking at the shooters
outside the hospital?
- 목표물 찾았나?
- 아뇨
- Do we have a target?
- Negative, sir.
그린한테 연결해줘
Patch me in to Green.
- 산소가 다 떨어졌어!
- 2%.
- I'm out of air!
거의 다 떨어졌어요
Almost nothing.
최대 2분이다!
Couple of minutes, max!
코브라,독수리팀을 지원 보내주겠다
Cobra,
I'm gonna peel off Vulture
to give you reinforcements.
아닙니다 너무 멀리있습니다
No, it's a negative, sir.
They're too far away.
시간내에 오지 못합니다.
They will never
get here in time.
-생각이 있습니다
-알겠다.
- But I got an idea.
- Copy that.
독수리팀은 창고를 기습한다.
Vulture Team preparing
to hit the warehouse.
인도하시오
Lead the way.
어디 있는거죠?
Where are they?
Aah! Aah!
수류탄!
Grenade!
Aah!
크루즈,상항보고 하라
Cruz, what's your status?
지붕에 접근하기 위해
계단으로 가고 있다
We're on the stairs
approaching the roof.
10초 남았다
10 seconds out.
Check.
얘야 우린 요게 있어
We got this, boy.
걱정마
No worries.
분대가 내려오는 중이야
Troops are on the ropes.
이제 흩어진다
Extracting now.
포지션 잡음
We're in position.
진입준비
Stand by to engage.
잡아버려!
Get them!
_
Aah!
Unh!
쓰러졌다!
Man down! Man down!
젠장!
여기 의사가 필요하다
Damn it!
We need the doc out here!
타이거 1팀하고 연료탱크에
같이 있습니다
Sir, he's still with Tiger 1
by the fueling station.
사령관님...
Commander...
전 모가디슈에서
1년간 의료진이었어요
I worked a year in a trauma ward
in Mogadishu.
준비해요
Gear up.
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
버텨 크루즈
Stay with me, Cruz.
버텨야한다
Just stay with me.
You get him stabilized,
부축해서 해안가로 데려와
you get the hell off the beach.
적들의 공격으로부터 벗어나
그 곳으로 오도록
First whiff of hostilities,
you are out of there.
알겠나?
You got it?
잘 알겠습니다
I read you loud and clear,
Commander.
TAO, 5인치포를 사격모드로 전환해서
TAO, I want 5-inch and CIWS
in surface mode
해안가를 겨냥한다
all focused on that beach.
알겠습니다
Aye, sir.
- 상태가 어때요?
- 당신이 왜 왔어요
- What have we got?
- What're you doing here?!
- 의사는 어딨죠?
- 연료팀과 같이 있어요
- Where's the doc?!
- He's up at the fueling tank.
기술팀장도 부상을 당했어요
Your Chief Engineer was injured,
as well.
내려놓아요
Lay him down.
내려놔.
Get him down.
여기요.
Here you go.
- 잡고
- 높이 들어요
- You, hold that.
- Set up a perimeter.
좋아요
All right.
Yes, sir.
제발
Come on.
피가 계속 나잖아요
기다려요!
He's gonna bleed out.
Just wait!
- 의사 부르라니까!
- 그럴 시간 없어요
- Somebody get the doc!
- Don't have time to wait!
우리가 못하면 아무도 못해요
There's nothing a medic can do
for this man that we cannot,
이 사람을 구하고 싶으면
so if you want
to help your friend,
계속 붙들고
내가 하라는 대로 하세요
just hold him still and listen
to every word that I say.
자, 날 보고 조금만 더 버텨
Hey, come on.
Stay with me. Look at me.
버텨 봐
괜찮아질거야
Stay with me.
You're gonna be all right.
제발 좀!
혈압 떨어져요
Let's go! Come on!
Blood pressure's dropping!
꽉 잡아요!
Hold that!
다시 들어갈테니
Going back in.
Okay.
제발
좀만 더 버텨라
Hey. Come on.
Stay with me. Look at me.
버티라고
Stay with me.
이제 못막으면 곧 죽어요
If you do not close this artery,
he's dead.
됐다!
Got it!
이제 진정됐어요
He's stabilized.
여어, 함장님.
Hey, Commodore.
물러서지 마시오
Don't give them a damn thing.
이 친구는 아미르요
This here is Amir.
미군을 족치는게 일상생활이고
He's a big fan of IEDs and
mutilating American soldiers.
아미르, 난 미 해군 톰 챈들러 대위다.
Amir, my name's Tom Chandler,
US Navy.
자네도 이러고 싶지 않을거야
You don't want to do this.
텍스는 널 풀어준 사람 아닌가?
Tex is the man who let you go
from your cells.
딴 놈과 다를게 없어
He is no different
from the others.
나도 처음부터 넌 별로였어
Hey, feeling's mutual,
you dirty--
독수리팀 나단 제임스--
상황보고 하라
Vulture Team, Nathan James--
I need a status update.
독수리팀, 나단 제임스--
무슨 일인가?
Vulture Team, Nathan James--
What is your status?
나단 제임스, 월터 1--
Nathan James, Walter 1--
우린 식료품 창고에 있다
We're at the food warehouse.
그런데 여기 인질이 있다
Just, uh... trying to deal
with a little hostage situation
- 여기에.
- 누구와 얘기하는거야?!
- over here.
- Who are you talking to?!
배에서 무전이 왔다.
I'm answering my ship's call.
응답하지 않으면
상황은 더 복잡해진다
Otherwise, they'll panic,
start shelling the whole place.
주의를 끌려고 하는 거야
He wants a diversion.
대화로 해결하자
That's all we're doing
is talking.
다른 사람 다치게 하지 말고
Let's not get anybody else
killed here.
No more talking to them!
You talk to me!
5인치 포 준비, 35번 빌딩을 조준해라
Prepare the 5-inch.
Focus fire on Building 35.
표적값 입력 대기중
Stand by for exact coordinates.
니시오카, 주시해
Nishioka, eyes on.
이 건물의 음식은 다 놔두고 가라
You will leave all food
on this side of the building.
그걸 어떻게 다 먹을려고
Ain't enough
of you bastards left
평생 먹을 거의 10배는 되겠다
to eat that much
in 10 lifetimes.
이봐.
Look.
아미르, 세상이 바뀌었다
Amir, it's a new world now.
이젠 나쁜놈도 없고, 좋은 놈도 없어
There's no good guys
and bad guys.
이제 모두 살아남기 위해
Doesn't matter which side
we thought we were on.
애쓰고 있을 뿐이다
We're all just trying
to survive.
자네가 생각하는 것 이상으로
자네들을 해치고 싶지 않다
We don't want to hurt you any
more than you want to hurt us,
하지만 난 우리편을
여기 두고 갈 수 없어
but you know I'm not leaving
here without my man, so...
텍스를 놔주면...
- 내가 텍스를 놔주면...
- When you let Tex go--
- If I let him go!
텍스를 놔주면
우리 갈 길을 가겠다
When you let him go,
we'll be on our way.
그리고 상의해서 식량을 나누자
I'll decide how much food
we leave you with.
안 돼지!
여긴 식량이 충분해!
No!
Enough of this!
내 말들어 아미르
Listen to me, Amir.
여긴 동서쪽 최대 식량창고다
You want the entire southwest
corner of the warehouse.
동서쪽 35번 빌딩이다 조준!
Focus fire at Building 35,
southwest corner.
이 지역 식량의 거의 절반이다
That's almost half the food
in the entire place.
그 정도면 충분하다고 생각하지 않나?
Is that gonna make you happy?
아니!
식량은 다 놔두고
No!
You will leave all the food
여기를 떠나라,
안 그러면 텍스는 죽는다!
on this side of the building
or he dies!
이런,세상은 바뀌었지만
Well, now, see, we got a bit
of a problem with that.
옛날법칙 가운데서 한가지
Because there's one thing
변함없이 적용되는 게 있지
from the old world
that still applies today,
그 한가지는 바로
something
that will never change.
목표물 고정
Target acquired.
발사!
Fire!
테러리스트와는 협상 안하는 것!
We don't negotiate
with terrorists.
상황종료!
Clear!
좋았어.
Nice.
그렇지.
Yes.
잘했어,훌륭해
Good work, good work.
배타는 거 좋아하는 지 모르겠지만
I don't know how you feel
about the water...
원한다면 언제든 환영해요
but we sure could use
your services.
어디로 가는데요?
Where you headed?
그전에 할 일이 있어요
We got some things to do,
임무가 완수하면
집에 갑니다
but when we're done,
we're going home.
좋아요. 타겠습니다.
Yeah, I'll sign up for that.
나단 제임스, 독수리 1--
인질극 상황종결
Nathan James, Vulture 1--
Hostage situation resolved.
지원 사격 고맙다
Thank you for the close shave.
귀환한다
We are inbound.
각자 위치로Now go to your stations,
Now go to your stations,
파도가 거세니
닻을 내린다.
all Special Sea
and Anchor Detail.
나단 제임스 함장께서
1700을 진행하실 것이다
Nathan James
will get underway at 1700.
모든 부서는 인원배치 하고
All departments make manned
and ready special reports
함교에 부장님께 작성할
특별 보고서 준비하도록
to the XO on the bridge.
함장님 오셨습니다
Captain's on the bridge.
오셨습니까.
Hey.
RHIBS(고무보트)와 SDV잠수함에
짐을 싣고 있고
We're loading up the RHIBs
and the SDV subs.
트럭들이 식량을
가져오고 있습니다
Trucks are bringing over
all the food.
5,6주는 먹을 수 있을 것 같습니다
Suppo thinks it's gonna last us
five, six weeks.
연료는?
And fuel?
탱크에서 공급받은 양중 96%를 잃었습니다
We lost suction on the tank
at 96%.
그리고 기술팀장이 파편에
찔려 부상당했습니다
Oh, and Chief Engineer
took some Shrapnel.
아주 침착하지만
She's gonna be okay, though.
괜찮아질겁니다
Tough as nails, that one.
음, 그냥 내버려 둬
Well, push comes to shove,
they all are.
저기..듣자하니 연구소의
기계중 하나가
Gentlemen, apparently,
one of the machines in the lab
웬일인지 엎어졌답니다
somehow got tipped over.
토펫 박사 말로는 배 운항하기 전에
Dr. Tophet is insisting
he needs time to secure
기계들을 재정비
할 시간을 달랍니다
and recalibrate the machines
before we move the ship.
얼마나?
How long?
3~4시간 달랍니다
He says three to four hours.
스캇박사는 어디에 있나?
Where's Dr. Scott?
아직 의료팀에...
Still in medical.
어려운 결정이었습니다
Was a tough call.
굉장한 하루였네.
We did good today.
함장님,항구쪽에서
교신이 잡히고 있습니다
Captain, I'm picking up
a contact headed for the harbor.
미확인 무전에,
Negative electronic signature.
저쪽에선 레이더가
작동중이지 않고
They're not operating
their radar.
신원불명입니다
Cannot make a positive ID.
관타나모 기지 남동쪽
21마일 거리에 있는 선박
Vessel 21 miles southeast,
Guantanamo Bay,
여긴 미 해군 군함151이고,
채널16으로 신호를 보내고 있다
this is US Navy Warship 151
hailing you on channel 16.
신원을 밝혀라, over.
Identify yourself, over.
여긴 영국 해군 군함이다
This is British Naval Vessel
HMS(중순양함)Suffolk(써퍽)...
HMS Suffolk...
확인해봐.
Confirm that.
..건조 번호 525,IMO IMO(국제해사기구)
무선신호 Whiskey Echo Bravo 236다
...hull number 525, IMO call
sign Whiskey Echo Bravo 236.
감연된 자는 없으며
식량이 떨어져가고있다
None of us have been infected,
but we're running low on food.
몇 주 동안 물자를 보충할 곳과
We've been searching for weeks
레이더 수리할 곳을 탐색중이다
for a place to replenish
and repair our radar.
확인됐습니다
Confirmed, sir.
난 톰챈들러 사령관이고
This is Commander Tom Chandler,
USS(미 해군 군함)나단 제임스의 함장이다
Commanding Officer,
USS Nathan James.
관타나모 기지에 온 걸 환영하는 바이며
We welcome you
to Guantanamo Bay,
몇 시간 전에 여길 왔었다면
although we wish you would've
been here a few hours ago.
우리가 도움이 됐을 것이오
We could've used the help.
다음번에 그러길
우리가 거기로 갈테니,
I assure you that next time,
we will be there for you,
받아들여주시오
should you choose to accept
an association.
음,포트 파이를 오븐에 넣고
Well, we'll put
some pot pies in the oven
생선과 감자튀김을 튀기려던 참인데
and some fish and chips
in the fryer.
어서 오시오
Come on in.
연구실 기계 고치기 전까지
움직일 수 없다
We can't go anywhere
till the lab's fixed.
새 친구들 한테 인사나 하자고
Let's prepare
to greet our new friends.
부함장 지시하게
XO has the lead.
아아아.
Ow.
으, 따가워요
Oh, that stings.
따갑겠지만, 소독해야해요
It's supposed to sting.
I'm cleaning it.
소독 안해도 되요
I don't need it cleaned.
아뇨 해야해요
Yes, you do.
조금 따가울거에요
This is gonna sting a little.
Ow.
Eng 어때?
How you doing, Eng?
괜찮습니다
All right, sir.
곧 나을거랍니다
Doc says I'll be on my feet
soon enough.
통제하고 있으니
서두를 것 없네.
No rush.
We got it all under control.
박사님이 그를 구해줬어요
She saved him.
박사가 우리 모두를 구해줄걸세
She's gonna save us all.
그렇지 않소? 스캇박사
Right,
Dr. Scott?
음, 그랬으면 좋겠습니다
Well, hopefully,
we'll save each other.
정말 감정이 풍부한 사람이요
Real soulful, this one.
저들의 뻔뻔한 얼굴은
신경쓰지 마세요
You never mind them good looks,
that brassy exterior.
뭐요?
Word?
알고 있어요
다신 그러지 않을게요
I know--
Don't do it again.
당신을 증명하기 위해
아무 것도 하지마시요...
You don't have anything
to prove...
뭐든말이오
if that's what it was about.
다신 이러지마시오
And don't do it again.
Hey! 언니~!
Hey! Nursey!
여기 냉찜질좀 해줘
I need a cold compress here.
전리품
Spoils of war.
알다시피,그의 가족들에게
물건 보낼 준비를 해야해
You know, I should be getting
this stuff ready for his family.
그치만 어...
But, uh...
받을 사람조차 없어
there's nobody even
to give it to.
함장님 오셨습니다
Captain's on the bridge.
시야에 들어왔는가?
They in sight?
예.
Yeah.
선상에서 흑맥주 돌리는
소리도 들리는군요
I hear they serve Guinness
on board.
함장님, E-Dub에선
저 군함을 확인할 수 없었고
Sir, E-Dub can't confirm
the signature on that vessel,
영국 군함이 아닐 거랍니다
but they don't think
it's British.
러시아놈들이다
It's the Russians.
당장 전투배치 한다!
Set general quarters now!
전투배치!전투배치!
General quarters!
총원,
자신의 전투위치로!
All hands,
man your battle stations!
Bridge, TAO--
스컹크 알파 동력공급 됐음
사격 관제 레이더
SCUNK Alpha just energized
fire control radar.
저흰 십자선 상에 있습니다
We're in their cross hairs.
톰 챈들러 함장?
Captain Tom Chandler?
챈들러 사령관이오
This is Commander Chandler.
즉각 신원을 밝히시오
Identify yourself immediately.
그런 무례한 소개는 유감이오,
I am sorry to have made
such a rude introduction,
그렇지만,당신들이 우리가 원하는
뭔가를 가지고 있는 걸 알고있소
but I believe you have something
that I want.